The question of whether or not we are alone in the universe has been answered.
Independence Day is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Roland Emmerich.
Strange phenomena surface around the globe.
The skies ignite.
Terror races through the world's major cities.
As these extraordinary events unfold, it becomes increasingly clear
that a force of incredible magnitude has arrived.
Its mission: total annihilation over the Fourth of July weekend.
The last hope to stop the destruction is an unlikely group of
people united by fate and unimaginable circumstances.
Capt. Steven Hiller, played by Will Smith.
President Thomas J. Whitmore, played by Bill Pullman.
David Levinson, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Marilyn Whitmore, played by Mary McDonnell.
Julius Levinson, played by Judd Hirsch.
General William Grey, played by Robert Loggia.
Independence Day (also promoted as ID4) is a 1996 American science fiction action film directed by Roland Emmerich, written by Emmerich and the film's producer Dean Devlin, and
stars an ensemble cast that consists of Will Smith, Bill Pullman, Jeff Goldblum, Mary McDonnell, Judd Hirsch, Margaret Colin, Randy Quaid, Robert Loggia, Vivica A.
Fox, James Rebhorn, and Harvey Fierstein.
The film focuses on disparate groups of people who converge in the Nevada desert in the
aftermath of a worldwide attack by a powerful extraterrestrial race.
With the other people of the world, they launch a counterattack
on July 4—Independence Day in the United States.
While promoting Stargate in Europe, Emmerich conceived the film while
answering a question about his belief in the existence of alien life.
Devlin and Emmerich decided to incorporate a large-scale attack having noticed that aliens in most
invasion films travel long distances in outer space only to remain hidden when reaching Earth.
Shooting began on July 28, 1995, in New York City, and
the film was completed on October 8, 1995.
Considered a significant turning point in the history of the Hollywood blockbuster, Independence Day was at
the forefront of the large-scale disaster film and sci-fi resurgence of the mid-late 1990s.
It was released worldwide on July 3, 1996, but began showing on July 2 (the same day the film's story
begins) in original release as a result of a high level of anticipation among moviegoers.
The film received mixed reviews, with praise for the performances, musical
score and visual effects, but criticism for its characters.
It grossed over $817.4 million worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1996 and the
second-highest-grossing film ever at the time, behind Jurassic Park (1993).
The film won the Academy Award for Best Visual Effects and was
nominated for the Academy Award for Best Sound.
The sequel, Independence Day: Resurgence, was released 20 years later
on June 24, 2016, as part of a planned series of films.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, showdown,
independence, patriotism, countdown.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.